# Almir Zariqi

Date of birth: 15 Mar 1981 Nationality: Kosovar Gender: Male (+383) 44164631 almir z@hotmail.com – almirzarigi11@gmail.com

Ferizaj, Kosovo

About me:

Dedicated and hardworking IT Administrator skilled at managing networking systems, updating hardware, software, and databases. Skilled HVAC foreman with more than 6 years of experience in the industry. Demonstrated ability to lead a team of technicians, manage projects, and ensure performance satisfaction. Seeking an opportunity to use my expertise and experience to help a growing company meet its goals.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

FEB 2019 - MAY 2021 - Ferizaj, Kosovo

#### IT ADMINISTARATOR - INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER 'NEGENET'

- · Diagnose desktop, applications, and any other issues of associated infrastructure and networks.
- · Maintain and format computers, laptops, and IT equipment such as printers, storage devices etc.
- Administer policies and procedures in the IT department.
- Install and support telecommunications equipment.
- Responsible for maintaining new installations and keeping a record of all detected issues.
- Work closely with the software supplier to resolve operational issues.
- DHCP, TCP / IP, Ethernet, Wireless Router, and Firewall Configurations.
- Maintain, install, upgrade, and configure data systems, administer operating systems, and maintain basic security and recovery procedures such as scheduling and backups.

DEC 2015 - JUN 2018 - Bagram, Afghanistan

### HVAC GENERAL FOREMAN - LOGCAP IV - FLOUR CORPORATION

- Perform all aspects of HVAC and mechanical systems operations; operation; developing, directing, and performing preventive maintenance of heat plant systems.
- Monitor building and automation systems for HVAC and fire hazards.
- Monitor, feed, and return water pumps, sump and chemical pumps, water softeners, internal and external boiler components, and related electrical systems.
- Maintain fuel system components, conduct water treatment tests, Monitor and repair geothermal pumps, maintain heat exchangers, sand traps, check valves, and pneumatic and automatic piping systems.
- · Oversee and direct staff and related daily operational activities in this occupational area.
- Schedule work, establish and adjust work schedules, evaluate staff performance, complete timesheets, accident reports, and work orders, coordinate work with contractors, train staff in HVAC and mechanical systems operations and maintenance.
- Manage all facilities of the HVAC O&M department in Bagram.
- Oversee and handle incoming service calls, daily work orders, and PM assignments for technicians.
- Perform troubleshooting and spot inspections on Foreman's performance and callbacks to ensure quality assurance.
- $\circ$  Ensure the HVAC O&M stays in compliance with all priority tickets.
- · Maintain schedules that ensure an adequate workforce was provided for all related projects.
- Use the MAXIMO system to track priority work orders, PM tickets, and Project work orders.
- $\circ$  Supervise 80 members of personnel in the HVAC department and assure safety practices are being implemented.
- Inspect fieldwork to evaluate construction and O&M quality and progress.

NOV 2012 - DEC 2015 - Bagram, Afghanistan

## **HVAC FOREMAN - LOGCAP IV - FLOUR CORPORATION**

• Establish the process required to fully execute the requirements of services and responsible for the quality, cost, and execution of HVAC mechanical services.

- Utilize pipefitting, refrigeration, structural layout, direct HVAC mechanics activities; installation, services, and repair air conditioners, environmental-control and other establishments.
- · Assemble ductwork and chassis parts using portable metalworking tools and welding equipment.
- Install compressor and condenser units using hand tools, follow blueprints or engineering specifications.
- · Connect motors, compressors, temperature controls, humidity controls and circulating ventilation fans.

MAY 2010 - NOV 2012 - FOB Sharana, Afghanistan

#### **HVAC JOURNEYMAN - LOGCAP IV - FLOUR CORPORATION**

- Perform preventive and schedule maintenance on all HVAC equipment, systems, and controls.
- Perform in-depth overhaul and installations.
- Operate with MAXIMO and other various forms of logistic requisitions.
- Responsible for new work requests, estimates, and Letters of Technical Directives for the entire HVAC department
- Install, maintaining and repairing ventilation and air conditioning systems and equipment.
- Identify maintenance risks on equipment.
- Diagnose electrical and mechanical faults for HVAC systems.
- Clean, adjust and repair systems, and perform warranty services.
- Provide technical direction and on-the-job training.

FEB 2007 - DEC 2009 - Ferizaj, Kosovo

## JOURNEYMAN ELECTRICIAN - ELECTRO AM

- Install and preserve the functionality of wires, plugs, panelboards, switchgear, switchboards etc. Size cables through different private or constructional residential and business buildings.
- Set up and maintain electrical machines.
- Monitor inventory to ensure an adequate stock.
- Diagnose and troubleshoot faulty wiring.
- Check for and deploy upgrades of electrical components.
- Facilitate order of needed electrical components.

MAR 2001 – JAN 2007 – Ferizaj, Kosovo

# IT TECHNICIAN - INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER 'NEGENET'

- Establish a network operations Center in Ferizaj to provide network support to customers.
- Provide high-quality network service, 24/7 customer support.
- $\circ$  Responsible to monitor the Operation and Performance of the network,
- $\,{}^{\circ}$  Provide troubleshooting to identify and solve any kind of network irregularity.
- Provide broadband, wireless and wired internet by using a carrier-class fiber-optic network.
- Maintain, fix, and update various computer hardware and software.
- Provide service in rural areas, by connecting small communities to central satellite access hubs.

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

OCT 2020 – CURRENT – Pristina, Kosovo

## BACHELOR OF SCIENCE - CYBER SECURITY ENGINEERING - Riinvest College

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- ∘ ESCO Institute EPA certification Certificate NO.69802553020 (UNIVERSAL) September 2011
- · Certificate of appreciation for excellent performance at work by LOGCAP IV HVAC / Afghanistan
- ∘ ICT Skills Development Training for Cyber Security Practitioner September 2021 January 2022 ∘ Training RIT A.U.K CCNA FastTrack April 2022 (ongoing)

# **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Microsoft Office | Zoom | HTML | JavaScript (Basic) | MAXIMO | Microsoft Windows | Nikto | Suite | Kali Linux | Metasploit Framework | Maltego | DnsRecon | WPScan | Drib | Wireshark | SQL Injection | Brute Force Attack | Dirbuster | Burp Suite | Owasp ZAP | Nmap | Reconng | Hydra | Zap | Nessus | Skipfish | Social Engineering Toolkit | Sqlmap |

# **LANGUAGES**

# **ALBANIAN: Native Language**

**ENGLISH:** Fluent

TURKISH: Intermediate SERBIAN: Intermediate